(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
PROTOLIVE 2022.12.26 21:00- in HoloEarth
スクリーンショットのSNSへの投稿 SNSへの動画の投稿
Posting screenshots and videos to social media is allowed.
配信・録画・ミラー配信 違法アップロード
Restreaming, recording, and illegal uploads are prohibited.
公式ハッシュタグ #ホロアースライブ
Official Hashtag: #HoloearthLive
開演までしばらくお待ちください...
Please wait a moment until the performance begins...
#ホロアースライブ
#HoloearthLive
#HoloEarthLive
PROTOLIVE
捕まえて ほら
Catch me, see?
この瞬間
This moment
Take a step
A world of our fiction awaits
Let's go!
Dawn Blue
ずっと同じ毎日に迷い込んでも
Even if I get lost in the same daily routine
気付かないフリをしてたんだ
I was pretending not to notice
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくて
I still couldn't find just a little bit of courage
紛れ込む宇宙(そら)で彷徨っていた
I was wandering in the blending sky
夜空に浮かぶ星に願いをかけるんだ
I make a wish on a star floating in the night sky
I hope 抱いてる夢を絶対諦めたくない
I hope... I never want to give up on the dream I hold
走り出すから
Because I'm starting to run
追いかけて 今 あの瞬間
Chase it, now, that moment
Take a step
見たことのないストーリー 進んでいくんだ
I'm moving forward into a story I've never seen
いつの日か描いた 世界へ辿り着けるように
So that I can reach the world I once envisioned
Let go of the past that's already gone, tomorrow's rolling in
Is it the world we know or the dream we sought so long?
もっと誰でもない自分になりたいんだ
I want to become a self that is like no one else
新しい風が心を揺らした
A new wind shook my heart
It takes something to believe
The wish we were promised will really come to life
And so, if this is how our story goes
Find that strength inside and remember what we've got
You took my hand and you said...
捕まえて ほら
Catch me, see?
この瞬間
This moment
Take a step
さあ 惑わずに 踏み出して 恐れずに行こう
Come, don't be confused, step out, let's go without fear
いつの日か描いた まだ見ぬ世界へ辿り着けるように
So that I can reach the yet-unseen world I once envisioned
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn
眩いブルーの空に溶けていく
Is melting into the dazzling blue sky
You and I in the undecided future
Doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Because morning is about to start moving
抱きしめて 今
Hold me, now
この瞬間
This moment
Take a step
見たことのないストーリー
A story I've never seen
I'll be here betting on that fierce heart
Somehow
Through that moment, take a start
It's all for now baby if you take that step
In the darkness you'll find me
Running by your side until the dawn
In the end, it's you and me
...against tomorrow.
Chase the world that we have dreamed.
Dry your eyes and don't look back.
皆さん、ともこんにちは！
Hello everyone!
調子どうですか？
How are you doing?
hololive Englishの森カリオペです！
I'm Mori Calliope from hololive English!
あ〜、すごく楽しかったね。
Ah, that was so much fun.
このライブ、めちゃめちゃ素敵ですね。
This live is really wonderful.
メタバースすごい！わ〜！
Metaverse is amazing! Wow!
あ〜、この曲ね、懐かしいね、ホロライブオルタナティブ。
Ah, this song brings back memories, Hololive Alternative.
でも、あの、日本語のリリックも英語のリリックも
本当に特別だから
But, you know, both the Japanese and English lyrics
are really special,
これからでもよく聴いてほしいね。
so I hope you'll continue to listen to them often.
じゃあ、皆さん、メタバースライブ
楽しんでくださいね！
Well then, everyone, please enjoy
the Metaverse live!
ゆら ゆら 動いた この心とも
Gently, gently, my heart moved along too
私はあの子になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that girl
ゆら ゆら 風吹く 連れ去っていく
Gently, gently, the wind blows and takes me away
いいな いいな 私はさ 何も持ってなかった
It's nice, it's nice. I didn't have anything.
canopus
作詞/作曲/編曲 瀬名航
AZKi
振付 中川大二朗
canopus
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Wataru Sena
AZKi
Choreography: Daijiro Nakagawa
傾いてる気分を無視した
I ignored my listing feelings
今日も無理して頑張っちゃうからな
Because I'm going to push myself and work hard today too
振れ私 振れ私 進めるさ
Shake me, shake me, I can move forward
今すぐに手に入れたいけど お預けかもね
I want to get it right now, but it might be put on hold
もしも今 叶うなら 届けたい
If it could come true now, I want to reach out
キラ キラ 輝け あの星みたいに
Sparkle, sparkle, shine like that star
あの子は私になれなかったんだ
That girl couldn't become me
キラ キラ 顔出す 嫉妬も正義も
Sparkle, sparkle, peek out, both jealousy and justice
そうか そうね あなたもさ ずっと一緒だった
I see, that's right. You were always together too.
キラ キラ 変わった この心そうだ
Sparkle, sparkle, it changed, yes, this heart
私はあの子にならなかったんだ
I didn't become that girl
キラ キラ 季節を 増やしてみる
Sparkle, sparkle, I'll try to increase the seasons
そうだ そうだ 私はさ 全て持っている
That's right, that's right. I have everything.
ゆら ゆら 変わった この未来ども
Gently, gently, it changed, even this future
私はあの子にならなかったんだ
I didn't become that girl
ゆら ゆら 掴んだ この運命と
Gently, gently, I grasped it, with this fate
生きてみたい みんなとさ 今を離さないように
I want to try living with everyone,
so as not to let go of the now
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
Virtual Singer、ホロライブ所属、AZKiです！
Virtual Singer, from hololive, I'm AZKi!
みんな楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?
はい、ホロアース...
Yes, HoloEarth...
ライブということで
Since it's a live performance...
みんなね こう自由に動きながら
everyone can move around freely...
好きな場所で見れるということで 新しい形のライブですね
and watch from wherever they like, so it's a new style of live show.
普段と違ってもういろんな角度から
Unlike usual, being watched from so many different angles...
見られているというライブ 大変緊張しております
in this live show, I'm very nervous.
はい そして さきほどの楽曲はAZKiのオリジナル楽曲
Yes, and that last song was an original AZKi song,
「Canopus」でした 皆さん いかがでしたでしょうか？
it was "Canopus". Everyone, how did you like it?
はい ちょっとね この空間で「Canopus」を歌えて かなりテンションが上がりました
Yes, singing "Canopus" in this space really got my energy up.
はい ということで 次で早くも 最後の曲ということなんですけれども
Yes, so the next song is already the last one, but...
みんな 最後まで盛り上がってってくれますかー！？
is everyone ready to rock out until the end!?
おー！
Oh!
はい ということで 最後まで盛り上がっていきましょー！
Okay, let's keep the energy up until the very end!
Story time
作詞 meg rock
Lyrics meg rock
作曲 山田高弘
Music Yamada Takahiro
編曲 齋藤真也
Arrangement Saito Shinya
幾千の星の物語
Stories of thousands of stars
長い長い旅の終わりに
At the end of a long, long journey
僕の瞳に降り注いで
Pouring into my eyes
魔法を解ける
The magic is broken
この胸の星の物語
This story of stars in my heart
高鳴る鼓動を その先に
Beyond the racing pulse
待ってる その続きを
I'm waiting, for what comes next
もっと知りたいんだ
I want to know more
僕の声になる前の囁きが
Before the whisper before it becomes my voice
ざわめきに解けてしまう前に
dissolves into the bustle
煌めく流れ星になって
Become a twinkling shooting star
空を駆ける
and run through the sky
たとえ今はどんなに小さくても
No matter how small it is now
ほんのささやかな羽ばたきでも
even just a tiny flapping of wings
世界はきっと僕ら次第
The world is surely up to us
どんなときでも
no matter when
囁き つぶやき ほんの少しの勇気
Whispering, muttering, just a little bit of courage
羽ばたけ 瞬け 世界は明けなく変わる
Flap your wings, twinkle, the world changes instantly
ざわめき ひらめき 幾つの波を越えて
Bustling, flash of inspiration, crossing many waves
煌めき ときめき 君に届け
Twinkling, heart-pounding, let it reach you
重力から解き放たれて
Released from gravity
大人への魔法を脱ぎ捨てて
stripping away the magic of adulthood
子供の時のその気持ちで
With those feelings from childhood
めくるページで
on the turning pages
過去のすべて星座のように
Everything in the past, like constellations
つながって答えを描いた
connected and drew the answer
涙の海の果ても
The end of the sea of tears
笑顔の空の色も
and the color of the sky of smiles
この胸に光ってる
Shining in this chest
僕だけの物語
my very own story
僕の声になる前の囁きが
Before the whisper before it becomes my voice
ざわめきに解けてしまう前に
dissolves into the bustle
煌めく流れ星になって
Become a twinkling shooting star
君を見つける
and find you
たとえ今はどんなに小さくても
No matter how small it is now
ほんのささやかな羽ばたきでも
even just a tiny flapping of wings
世界はきっと僕ら次第
The world is surely up to us
どんなときでも
no matter when
いつまでも
Forever
どんなときも 僕ら次第だから
No matter when, because it's up to us
囁き つぶやき ほんの少しの勇気
Whispering, muttering, just a little bit of courage
羽ばたけ 瞬け 世界は明けなく変わる
Flap your wings, twinkle, the world changes instantly
ざわめき ひらめき 幾つの波を越えて
Bustling, flash of inspiration, crossing many waves
煌めき ときめき 君に届け
Twinkling, heart-pounding, let it reach you
ありがとう！
Thank you!
楽しかったね。
That was fun.
はー、皆さん、森カリオペです。
Hello everyone, I'm Mori Calliope.
わー、AZKi先輩すごーい！ 本当に素敵でしたねー！
Wow, AZKi-senpai is amazing! That was truly wonderful!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
この曲はね、本当に好きです。
I really love this song.
いろんな才能があるシンガーがいるから
Because there are singers with so many different talents...
めっちゃめっちゃ素敵で
it's just so, so wonderful.
…な曲になった。
...it turned into such a great song.
私もずっと歌ってみたいと思ってたけど、
I've always wanted to try singing it too,
今回ね、頑張りました。
but this time, I really gave it my all.
というわけで、今回のライブは以上となります。
And with that, this concert has come to an end.
あっという間の時間でしたが、
It felt like it was over in the blink of an eye,
今後もホロアースではいろんなライブや
but it seems there will be many more concerts and
イベントをやっていくみたいなので、
events in Holoearth in the future,
皆さん期待して待ってて下さい！
so please look forward to them!
そして、メタバースでのライブということで、
And, since this is a concert in the metaverse,
リアルな会場でのライブになかなか足を運べない人たちも、
even those who can't easily make it to a physical venue
これから同じ空間で一緒にライブが楽しめるようになる
will be able to enjoy concerts together in the same space.
ということで今から私たちも楽しみです！
We're already looking forward to it!
皆さん、楽しかった？
Everyone, did you have fun?
それでは皆さん、今日はありがとうございました！
Well then, everyone, thank you so much for today!
またね！
See ya!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for coming!
本日はご視聴いただきありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching today!